Good afternoon, good evening.
Welcome folks to session 10 and our third
to last session of Empower Labs cohort
four.
Today we're focused on identifying your
business's competitive advantage.
So we'll be examining systematic and
data-driven approaches to maintaining
market leadership.
AI enablement has allowed us to do what
would have historically taken months to do
in your days or weeks.
And we need to be using these tools to
future-proof
businesses
we go ahead and look at the program
timeline, this is our third session together
this week, and we meet again on Monday
and then have our final session next Friday.
I'm gonna go ahead and launch our poll.
So we are launching our poll here, looking
at our milestone check-in.
This week, we asked you to prepare for
implementation and create your initial
implementation plan.
Looking at the responses, some of you are
in progress.
Some of you have not yet started.
And that's totally okay.
A reminder that this is a transformation.
So taking all the time that you need to do
these exercises, thinking deeply about your
business and being strategic and
systematic is important.
You'll continue to have access to the
curriculum after we wrap next week.
So you can continue to go through the
program at your pace.
looking to see if anyone is willing to share
in the chat what your insights are around
prioritizing and creating your
implementation plan.
We have a few minutes to sort of talk
through some of that if there's any
interest.
Is everyone feeling Zoom shy today?
Okay.
Okay, so what we're covering today is the R
in empower.
So this is for robust market position.
If you think about the three layers of
business process, we're at the enabling
processes layer.
We're looking at how to position your
business to stand out in the marketplace.
Today, we're covering three main things.
First, we're looking at leveraging AI to
monitor competitors, predict shifts, and
build your defensible advantages.
Then we're going to be looking at product
or service expansions.
And finally, we're going to examine how to
future-proof and right-size your business.
And with that, I'm going to throw it over to
Hayden to get us started.
Thank you, Midori.
this is a...
somewhat different approach to this
session, because AI is actually just so good
at this particular piece.
I decided I'd sort of talk and give examples
of what it can do, as well as actually just
give examples of prompts that you can
bring to Claude.
The way I would actually recommend using
this, obviously, we're going to talk and
present and go back and forth and have a
Q&A.
but I would recommend taking this deck
after the fact and anything that seems
relevant, like literally just using some of
the prompts because it's the easiest way to
kind of see what AI can do for you.
As Murray said, we're sort of splitting this
up into three different parts.
So we're gonna go over sort of the external
market view first.
So one thing that AI can do is it can actually
sort of analyze industry trends as well as
competitor moves.
This is something that pretty much every
small business doesn't have time to do, but
it's something that's very simple to set an
agent up to do or a simple cron job to do,
you know, something similar to that
competitor report we did back in session
five and just see what might be changing,
what risks might exist, right?
If you have regulatory risks, you might
want to be checking news items related to
that.
I know one of our businesses had a fairly
large regulatory shift about six months ago
that we were actually able to learn about
through AI before it happened, which was
nice.
There's also a predictive approach to
basically anything that has data related to
your customers,
even social media and sentiment analysis.
And obviously being able to do this can give
you a strong competitive advantage.
So one of the things that you can start
testing with and you can start using sort of
like deep research style prompts is just
analyze industry trends, right?
What should we prepare for?
You can ask it to use the PESTLE
framework, which is P-E-S-T-L-E, if you want
to give it like an actual framework to
follow.
And yeah, you'll be amazed at what it
knows, especially because you have a
master prompt that AI understands your
business well.
So as we go, if anyone has any questions,
feel free to type it in the chat.
Midori, I'm not looking at the chat, but you
can interrupt me.
So just because we may have questions
related to each individual slide.
The other thing that you can do very easily
with AI is you can actually size your
market.
Again, a lot of people haven't actually sized
their market or haven't sized their market
since they started their business maybe
and did a business plan in the first place.
Um, and they don't actually even know
their market share.
Um, so, you know, typically when, as a,
from a diligence perspective, we're always
trying to determine, you know, market
share of a business before we buy.
Um, so understanding the difference
between your total addressable market,
your TAM and your SAM, which is your
serviceable addressable market, um, is
something very useful and understanding
how to sort of bring your SAM closer to
your TAM, um, over time is, uh, something
that AI can, can help you plan.
Obviously entering new markets,
expanding, basically expanding service
area is something that can be done much,
much quicker now.
So on that note, you can look at geographic
analysis, market size by region.
If you have a service business, for example,
and your techs bring their trucks home
with them, technically you can create more
GMB listings and expand your market that
way because technically you're
serviceable area is really the cumulative
radius around where your techs live.
Same goes for if you have a construction
business, that I've had certain businesses
be able to expand their footprints by either
storage unit rentals, depending on what
the business is, or even RVs.
And going further out, you can obviously
basically do a prompt like, you know,
analyzing your market opportunities by
market size competition level and entry
difficulty, and basically priority stack
different ways either to expand
geographically or potentially to expand
through sort of vertical integration, adding
new products to the same customer base.
So here's just an example.
By doing this, you may start expanding
your verticals.
Certainly, we've done that in some of our
companies.
Another question is, and this is a question
that is somewhat uncomfortable, but is
also quite quite illuminating, which is what
would your AI native competitor look like?
So if someone, if someone, if I were to start
your business today, right.
And someone were to look at how can I,
you know, automate acquisition and
ideally automate, you know, pieces of
delivery.
and scale pieces of delivery.
How can I use predictive success and how
can I expand globally even?
That sort of gives you an idea of what the
space could look like and also where some
opportunities could be.
And so one of the prompts that's really
interesting, and again, you could just
screenshot this slide and put it into cloud
and just say like, do the prompt at the
bottom and we'll then have the context,
everything else here.
but describe an AI first competitor in my
industry.
What would their operations look like?
What would their pricing be like?
What would the customer experience be
look like?
Uh, what would the 80, 20 of fulfillment
look like if, um, fulfillment was just the
piece that was delivered on the computer,
right?
Which may not be your exact competitor.
It may be, um, a facet of the industry that
becomes AI native.
Um, and that on its own can be, um,
I mean, a lot of people have found massive
business opportunities and some pivots by
doing this prompt.
Um, so in terms of how AI first companies
operate, I, so they have automated
workflows and decisions, right?
Instead of manual process processes and
handoffs, uh, they have AI power quality
assurance instead of human dependent
quality control.
What that means is they need to have a lot
more predictability, right?
Um, so some of the workflows need to be a
bit narrower than what humans can
handle.
Um, obviously exponential scaling and 24
seven global operations.
It means, again, an AI-first company would
want a significantly narrower scope on
what they do, but a potentially infinite
scope on who they do it for and when they
do it.
So how they'll take customers and how
they'll take market share from you and
others would be around predictive lead
scoring.
Obviously, this can be done almost entirely
automatically.
It can be done through simple research,
like all you really need.
You can get somebody's name and zip code
or name and even city.
AI can go out and scrape data.
tons and tons and tons of information
about that person.
And then use that not only for sort of lead
scoring, but use that for automated
nurture with personalized videos and
experiences.
And, you know, the, the top, the top
companies will have this continuous
optimization of kind of getting a customer
in nurturing them with personalized
videos, better and better and split testing
constantly.
This is something that, you know,
we're focusing on a lot right now in our
companies.
And then the other piece here is obviously
anything that is on a computer, there will
be a massive cost collapse on.
And that over time, that means there's like
a limited arbitrage window, right?
Where, you know, the first companies to do
this will probably just enjoy, either enjoy a
very nice margin expansion for a period of
time or, you know, steal a bunch of market
share quickly.
But I would say most things that are
delivered on a computer will probably have
an 80% cost collapse, potentially more.
And that makes a lot of things that weren't
viable before viable today for those
companies, right?
So, you know, you can make, freemium
becomes viable for a lot of things that used
to cost significant, like a significant amount
of money, right?
I mean, you've probably seen, you know,
lead magnets today are things that would
have been, you know, charged two or $300
for in the past.
So I think we'll see significantly more of
that.
Again, if you wanted to kind of explore
what this looks like, you could just
screenshot the slide, put it in and have a
conversation with Claude about your
particular industry.
So before we move into the next part, I'm
curious to hear from you.
What questions are coming up in terms of
like, you know, an AI first version of your
business or making certain aspects of your
business AI first?
Or have you already seen competitors
popping up doing some of this?
I have a question.
After you, Don.
I always jump in first.
You go ahead.
Thank you.
It's not so much a question, but just more
of an experience and a reflection and love
to hear your perspective.
Some context, I run a digital agency.
I have another business signed up with an
AI first agency.
unbeknownst to them that I was in the
business and went through as if I was a real
prospect.
And I did the same with my team,
unbeknownst to them, just to see the real
experience of a human-centered digital
agency approach and a completely AI one.
And they came back with a
recommendation to spend $90,000 in the
first month because that's what the AI said
versus what our team came up with, a
slow...
gradual test, look at the data, et cetera.
And so I was completely disenfranchised
and almost pissed that they could come up
with that.
Yet at the same time, I'm respecting where
the industry is going.
So I don't really know how to respond to
that.
If I just shut it down and say it's too AI and
there's no real human-centered approach,
that could be completely ignorant.
So I'm just perplexed with how to look at
what's coming down there and put it into
context with where I am with my company
to make sure we're not left behind.
And it sounds like, um, you just found a
poor quality version of this.
Um, because I think if you even ask Claude
today, if you said, Hey, just, you're my
CMO, take over all my marketing, what do I
do?
It's not going to tell you to spend $90,000,
um, upfront.
Um, So I wonder what context it has.
I wonder how it's trained, like what data
sets it's trained on, because that's clearly
not best practice in the industry.
Well, they're backed by Anderson Horowitz
and have raised a bunch of money and
they're here to play and have scaled to 850
customers in 12 months.
So impressive from that perspective.
But just from my experience...
it was completely not what I think even an
AI enabled agency should be.
I mean, it disenfranchised me, but yet
they've had success and I credit them.
So I'm, I'm torn.
I just don't know how to digest it all.
Yeah.
So I think, first of all, there's not really a AI
first agency here without a, like a human, a
proper human layer, a human in the loop
and a taste layer.
Um, I don't think that really exists today,
especially if you call it like digital agency,
meaning, um, you know, we customize the
client, we do multiple acquisition channels,
et cetera.
Um, I think you may see, you know, very
specific by acquisition channel sort of AI
first options.
Um, but even with an agency, like if you
think about.
So an agency fundamentally your unit
economics, you, you have, um, account
managers.
Right.
And account managers are able to fulfill a
certain number of accounts.
And then you typically have sort of back
office folks doing, you know, whatever the,
the work is, whether it's SEO or ad buying
or anything.
So like the cost collapse there is that the
account manager can probably handle
three to four X, the accounts by taking a lot
of the communication and turning them
from meetings into reports.
Right.
And strong, like automated videos.
So whereas an account manager might
have done maybe a meeting every two
weeks or a meeting every week or a
meeting, you know, that might turn into a
meeting every month or a meeting every
eight weeks with a bunch of other updates.
And then obviously all the backend stuff
just turns to zero, very close to zero, right?
If I want to do, you know, if I want to go
build a hundred links and write a thousand
posts, you know, I can do that in cloud code
in a morning.
So, yeah, I don't know if that helps.
I think there's a staged approach and
everyone is still figuring it out.
And there's still a matter of sort of garbage
in, garbage out.
And at least from what you describe your
experiences, that it feels like garbage in,
garbage out, at least for your use case.
Because like I said, I think if you brought
this to Claude, the exact same idea, and I
don't think it would recommend you do
that.
at least not in my experience.
Thank you.
Don, did you have a question?
I don't want to take you off your track
here, but I really just wanted to invite you
to comment on if you have any insights
after you build one of these incredible CIA
dossiers on your prospect and you're
making custom approaches to them.
It gets a little creepy, doesn't it?
I mean, it depends.
It's creepy if you
I guess if you expose everything you've
learned, right?
But it's a lot like, I mean, it's a lot like
Facebook advertising, right?
So if I know, let's say for example, I have a
customer and all I have is their email, their
name email and their, I don't know, city,
right?
And I'm able to find through research,
through cloud code or clay or whatever, I'm
able to find their LinkedIn, able to find
their job.
Right.
And then I'm able to send, let's say
personalized videos around, you know,
showing them like like-minded folks that
have had success with my products or
services.
Right.
And so maybe they are a digital marketing
work in digital marketing or they own a
digital marketing agency.
And I can talk about my other customer
that, you know, was in digital marketing.
and had success and looks just like you,
right?
That's not necessarily creepy that there
might be a sense of how do they know this
or it might be a sense of sort of serendipity.
Like, oh, interesting, yeah.
So you do have to be careful, I would say,
but I think everyone will also just get very
used to it very quickly.
Thank you, please go on.
So product and service expansion.
This is one of the areas AI is just fantastic
at.
And one of the issues with a lot of small
businesses is that they actually don't have,
you know, they may not have a proper
upsell or a proper cross-sells within their
customer journey.
And that's a huge opportunity, right?
Obviously, if you're able to optimize for
that,
you can have stronger lifetime values.
If you have a stronger lifetime values, you
can pay more for a customer, other
marketing channels start opening up.
Right?
So in my opinion, a lot of businesses like
solving for lifetime value comes first and
almost every business that I start or buy, I
want to have like a full upsell in place,
usually within 90 days.
Right.
Even in power labs, we needed, we made
sure we have to have like something ready
within 90 days.
right?
Because that's what allows you to optimize
and basically be profitable on, on
advertising.
Um, so this entire piece, um, on expansion
opportunities, I basically allows you to
upload all your information, right?
I mean, already your master prompt knows
most of it and allows you to do an analysis,
you know, segment out your customers,
um,
and then come up with ideas for expansion
revenue per customer segment, right?
And so your basic calculation is your
current base rate times your adoption rate
times your average expansion revenue per
customer equals your gross potential.
And so you simply explain this, again,
screenshot, these slides were designed to
be screenshotted and put in, and then you
guys can have conversations.
But screenshot this, talk about it, and
you'll likely find a bunch of different
options to, again, prioritize and kind of
stack rank.
The beauty, again, of AI, especially if a lot
of these things are more digital in nature, I
mean, even if they're not digital in nature,
even if it's all, you know, even if you're
electricians or landscapers, the actual
creation of the product, the creation of the
process to do it, the go-to-market side of it
is done in probably 1 20th, maybe 1 30th of
the time.
that I used to take.
And we'll go over that in some of our other
slides.
We talked a little bit in one of the previous
sessions about the customer journey and
ascension points for customers.
This is another example of working with
LLMs to determine what are the actual
ascension points and automatic triggers.
And also as you're designing these new
paths for customers, how to design those
in Mayan, right?
So usage patterns, life cycle stages, stage
progression, support ticket themes.
I obviously, again, same idea, screenshot
this, talk about it if it's something that
you're interested in.
Um, one of the, one of the sort of software
and SAS metrics, um, that I love taking
from that space and bringing to other
customer companies is this idea of
expansion revenue, um, and like net
revenue retention, which is really huge in
SAS.
Um, it's huge in, you know, monthly
retainer style contracts, but not as big in
other companies.
Um,
So again, this is something you could bring
to an LLM and basically design a dashboard
to track expansion revenue success with
leading and lagging indicators.
This is another prompt that suggests,
especially if you don't understand this, you
kind of combine with some of the previous
slides to understand what this could look
like.
It was I think there's another slide on this
later, but I'll mention it now.
So you also want to create like a funnel.
So understand the funnels as you design
new products upsells.
So exactly what do the conversion points of
each layer of the funnel look like?
What are your conversion rates?
What's the expansion revenue?
Break that all down.
You can have Claude do that in a
spreadsheet for you.
if you want to play with it, or you can have
Claude just build up a little React app that
you can kind of customize and share.
If you're looking to product manage and
improve the product, more data is better,
right?
And so traditional prioritization is that
loudest customers get heard, right?
The squeaky wheel gets the grease or it's
ad hoc and owner opinion drives decisions.
So the AI driven version of this is that you
get your data in order first, and you feed AI
your data.
We'll go over that in the next section.
But you make this highly systematic.
So that is both in product roadmaps on
your own existing products and services,
but it's also in your expansion roadmap.
So for those who aren't doing it already, if
you have support tickets, if you have
support email, if you have usage analytics,
your Google analytics, your Facebook ads,
everything, your social mentions of your
CSAT surveys, all of this should be dumped
into AI.
The very, very basic version of this would
be just dump it into Cloud and have it
analyze it.
and have it create reports, the more
advanced versions of this would be to feed
it into a database.
I think we went over this briefly on the
office hours, but you can also, if you use
Obsidian, one thing you can also do is feed
it into Obsidian and have Obsidian
installed in wherever you have like Cloud
Code or Codex installed, and basically have
your Obsidian be a database and have a
vector layer above it to sort of get a
semantic searching.
We'll probably get into that in some videos
later.
Same idea here.
Use data to basically create service
development plans based on customer
feedback and competitive analysis.
Again, depends quite heavily on your niche.
So the next step, assuming you've found
something, you may have found an
interesting idea for product expansion, is
how do you kind of take the MVP lens,
right, and bring it to Cloud and accelerate it
through Cloud?
So the iteration feedback loop on
prototyping and MVP is like immediate
now.
It used to be that you had an idea, you sort
of created a plan, you brought it to a
developer, developer started building it
out, you tested it with customers, came
back and iterated.
Now you can just vibe code that.
So for those who have not vibe coded, AI
Studio is my favorite of the sort of just
online more or less free versions of doing
this if you're not already using Cloud Code
or Codex or something.
Um, so it's AI studio.google.com.
Um, here you can literally, so the little hack
for that is, uh, is a prompt like this, which
is like design a pilot test for the new
service.
Uh, and then as it goes on further, have it,
uh, design a, basically a product roadmap,
um, for it.
And then you just copy and paste that into
AI studio to follow it.
Um, so it's a PDR.
Another thing is like CBA.
So cost benefit analysis.
That's another thing that, you know, a
small business would almost never do.
Right.
To try to calculate expected value of a
project.
Right.
Now it's a single prompt.
And so just ask it to do a cost benefit
analysis.
Obviously, cloud understands this.
But anything that you've planned out, you
can fully understand the cost, the benefit
and map out.
the ROI.
The only thing to be really aware of here is
that Claude has a, all LLMs have a habit of
assuming that your costs, especially your
time costs for doing things, are the time
costs that things took pre-AI, right?
Because it's trained on that data.
It's trained on pre-AI data.
And so the I don't know if you've noticed
this, but sometimes you'll ask it to, you
know, create a plan and it'll say like this
one thing will take five hours and actually
something that takes like 15 seconds.
Right.
Um, that's because of what it's been
trained on.
So you need to be, if you do this, just be
careful on going back and forth on the
actual cost because cloud is like extremely
conservative because it's basing it on pre
AI, um, time analysis.
if you're planning out, um, any type of
capital allocation, right.
Whether that is, um, you know, an
acquisition of company, um, or whether
that's like the creation of a new, um,
acquisition channel or testing of a new
acquisition channel, uh, same thing.
Um, Claude is super, super helpful for this.
Um, if you're planning out, uh, a new
product service offering, um, and you do a
go-to-market analysis, I think we have that
in a later slide, Claude can pretty
accurately understand the acquisition cost
by channel based on benchmarks.
So this is always the first place I go when
thinking about testing out new channels.
I think we mentioned this in session five,
but just always make sure that you give
yourself enough time to test for channels
and that you budget enough.
Typically, I would say most channels will
not be profitable day one.
Most products you launch will not be
profitable day one.
There's a bunch of iteration.
The nice thing is that the iteration used to
take longer, right?
Now it's faster.
But I would still say, like, give yourself
three months to test out either a new
channel or a new product offering.
Ah, this was the slide I was looking for.
So this is basically modeling the funnel of
your revenue.
So lead to qualify to opportunities to
customers as an example.
So this is kind of the prompt.
So build a conversion funnel model for new
offering.
Again, screenshot this and put it in.
And ideally, you can ask it to do it in Excel
or you can ask it to do it as a React app.
either way, depending on what your
preference is.
If you're comfortable with Excel, use Excel,
I'd say.
Hayden, I'm just going to draw your
attention to a comment in the chat.
FM, do you want to ask that out loud?
Sure.
So back to that prior slide where
talk about the numbers.
As a member of Acquira, is this something
that you help your customers with as well?
Oh yeah.
I mean, this is, uh, yeah, this is the meat
and potatoes.
Like you have to understand the, I mean,
most of the companies that we buy at
Acquira are our cash.
It's like you're buying it based on cashflow
and a multiple of cashflow.
Um, so I would say most people who own
businesses aren't sometimes they're doing
that.
And then sometimes it's, uh, more of a tuck
in acquisition in which case, which can
often be even better, uh, from a numbers
perspective.
but you really do need to know your
numbers.
More like where this led up to as a part of a
roll-up strategy and looking at the different
opportunities that might exist by doing all
the tuck-ins.
Do you help think through all of that to
where there might be able to find hidden
jewels that are just sleeping?
Yeah, yeah.
So I just visited a company on Saturday.
They've done two tuck-ins.
Both tuck-ins were, from an EBITDA
perspective, EBITDA negative.
Both were like two-thirds seller financing
and very small tuck-ins, right?
Like 400K each.
And in both, just from the customer list
and using like Chirp to reach out to the
customer list, it's generating about 100K a
month in gross profit from just one of the
tuck-ins.
And it's doing that, I'd say, at probably
one-third the capacity it could, like 200
leads a day.
Um, so, so there are, this is something I
wouldn't have talked about doing because
it was very difficult to predict.
Um, and it was very difficult to have strong
conversion on, um, customer lists before
compared to today.
Um, but yeah, that's an example.
Uh, and in terms of like a roll up, uh, yeah,
you need to roll ups are, are are
complicated in the sense that like on, on
paper, the math looks great.
I'm going to roll up, you know, three or four
of these things that three X and then
combines they've got enough EBITDA for
like other financial buyers to be interested
and I'm going to go sell it.
Right.
There's a lot more to that.
Like there's a, there's a pretty deep
integration cost.
There's some, I think naivety and assuming
that financial buyers are completely
unsophisticated and they see a bigger
number and go for it.
Um, and I think also just understanding
like the exit is, is not easy.
Um, so I actually probably prefer rollups
where an exit is an exit is part of the plan.
Um, whether that's an exit because you
are, um, having like a partial exit, um, and
like raising more money to, to buy more,
um, or whether that's through something
like an ESOP, right.
Where you, or whether there is an actual
buyer already in place.
I think those things, doing a roll-up in that
environment makes a lot more sense than
just saying I'm going to buy three things
and sell it.
Thank you.
For capital allocation decisions, it can be
very difficult for small business owners to
have the discipline to basically reject, let's
say, deals, whether if you want to buy a
business or reject ideas that you may have
sort of become emotionally attached to.
So actually creating frameworks and
investment theses
for you and your business with AI is
extremely useful around capital allocation.
And this is, yeah, this is like the bread and
butter of Acquira in terms of having an
investment thesis to buy a business.
But I think this is also important for any
investment decision in your business,
right?
If I have, you know, you don't want, if you
have a million dollars in the bank and, you
know, that represents two years of OpEx
burn, like that's opportunity being lost.
So the question then is like, what's the best
way to, you know, spend a million bucks?
Is it to buy another company?
Is it to test new acquisition channels?
Is it to do this AI initiative?
You need to understand sort of what are
the, what's the framework to green light or
red light those initiatives?
And AI can do that for you.
So go-to-market is like a weird concept.
So go-to-market strategy is basically a
combination of several different things.
And if you ask Claude to do it, so something
like this, I would probably add to this
prompt to do everything in separate
artifacts.
Just asking Claude to give me a
go-to-market strategy canvas and put it in
new artifacts will get you a ridiculous
wealth of information.
Like I highly recommend you try this
prompt if you've never done this before.
It will do an analysis of, you know, your ICP
and segments of customer acquisition
channels and returns.
So often when I'm sort of just planning
something, I'll start with the go to market
and then sort of expands, you know, you
kind of like one, two punch,
This with like the prototyping prompts that
we had before.
And you can, you know, in a single hour or
two, like really fully understand like a long
roadmap of what launching something
would look like.
Quick question.
Sorry to interrupt Hayden on this
particular one.
Do you do the GTM prompt within your
existing project that you are in like HVAC?
Okay.
Not a new chat entirely.
Yeah.
So I'll do it in a new chat in my master
prompt project for the company I'm talking
about.
And so often this is also not just like a new
chat and then put this in, it'll be more like
I'll chat back and forth with Claude.
my way of chatting with Claude is always
ask me questions, right?
I want to do this, ask me questions, answer
your own questions, right?
That goes back and forth for a bit.
And so I might talk about, I'm thinking of
this new offering, you know, ask me some
questions on how it might work.
And then when it gets to a certain point, I
go to this and say, okay, great, create the
GTM.
And so then it has a ton of context about
what I'm looking for.
Thank you.
So part of GTM is acquisition channels,
right?
Some people here may not have a ton of
acquisition channels in place and may be
looking at testing out and launching
acquisition channels.
This is a great way to allow AI to help you
prioritize them.
Again, I would have a conversation back
and forth and then lead to something like
this.
Another interesting part of acquisition
channels and maybe the digital marketing
agency owners in the room will not like me
for saying this, but I, part of the ability of
creating process, right.
And being able to create like this whole
core process with blueprints and guides.
Part of that is nice to be able to document
what already exists, but I use it far more to
document what I'd like to do.
Right.
And so
If I wanted to, let's say I didn't know
anything about partnerships, right?
Influencer partnerships, but I heard it was
a good thing to do, or I didn't know
anything about LinkedIn, how to take
advantage of like LinkedIn organic, but I
knew it was a good thing to do.
The old way of doing this would be go hire
an agency, go hire consultants, have them
build this out for you.
One of the bad things about that is that
you don't, you often don't get any of the
domain expertise behind it.
So you, you often don't know whether the
consultant is actually good.
Um, and so something may not work out
and you may not know that it didn't work
out because it's the wrong channel for you,
or it didn't work out because of
incompetence.
Um, and I I've seen people go through like
four or five different agencies, um, or three
or four different agencies.
And they're just like, yeah, marketing
doesn't work in my business.
But the reality is that no, they just never
got a good agency.
Right.
And they didn't know.
Um,
The new way that I've been doing things is
actually having AI be my tutor and or my
team's tutor and have the AI build out all
the processes step by step.
And then we just follow them and we
iterate on them.
And so we've been calling this like
capability install kits, right?
So if we want to do a new thing, we literally
go out, we go into stage three and we just
like map out the entire process.
We understand it well.
And then someone on our team will
literally go through it.
There's still a world here for consultants
and agencies, but it's really more of a check
my work function as opposed to do my
work for me or even tell me what to do.
AI, in my opinion, and AI with this process
framework is significantly better at
defining what to do and how to do it, but it
doesn't have the taste and judgment that
an expert might have.
I would say that, yeah, there's a role for
consultants, but that role is possibly hourly
and it's possibly to involve them when
you've put, you know, the four or five
hours it takes to like literally map out an
entire capability.
Well, just on that note, you could say,
here's my framework or sell it or promote
the framework and then be the guide to do
it.
And that's your revenue model there.
So you take the agency completely out of
the equation, but you have the human
centered approach to execute.
Yeah, I mean, I think a lot of agencies will
have to go that the route of we'll train your
team and give you the capability.
So you can also, once you've got a
go-to-market in place, you can kind of
follow on to that prompt and have it
created like a go-to-market timeline.
So pre-launch, launch phase, growth phase,
et cetera.
Have it create the entire, you can have it
created as Gantt's, you can have it include
RACI.
Again, you may not use this in the type of
detail it gives you, but it's very useful to
just, because it takes nothing,
to do, it's very useful to see what that
might look like, right?
So it's almost like, it's almost like you're
previewing, you know, a path of an
alternative universe in the future.
Same thing goes with like launch
coordination, right?
Again, a lot of these things, when you think
of initiating something, you conflate or one
conflates many things into one and forgets
a lot of the details.
And so, you know, just understanding what
cross team or cross functional
dependencies might exist, what
communication would be needed, what
kind of tracking is needed, etc., is also very
useful.
Again, I look at this not as necessarily like,
this is my plan that I'm going to follow so
much as like, I want to preview, you know,
the actual amount of work it takes to do
this thing.
Yeah, so again, curious in terms of product
expansion, in terms like a GTM, what here
has kind of caught your attention or what
would you like to test or just chat about?
Yeah, I think we're a small enough group
that we can just stay in the and talk as a
group here.
I'm happy to go, but don't want to take all
the oxygen.
So if anybody else wants to say something.
Sorry.
Don here.
I just want to comment that there was a
comment in there about tracking progress.
And over the last couple of days, thanks to
Claude and my work here, I discovered that
I could create a pipeline product to keep
track of our progress and our various
initiatives.
Cloud took me over to a Supra database
and built out the whole SQL database and
the interface top to bottom.
So we're dumping FileMaker.
We're not doing any of the commercial
products.
We have a custom SQL database that we
can do anything with from here.
It took
took about 48 hours, you know, over a
couple of days.
It went from not just being an idea to I'm
launching it today.
And so, wow.
That's amazing.
I thought so.
Did you do it yourself, Don?
Yeah.
And what kind of background do you have?
Just for other people to understand, like,
do you have a technical background?
Did you know what relational databases
were?
Like, had a I will say about 2005, I hired a
team in India to build out a MySQL
database to create this product that I
thought would be extremely valuable.
I spent about $25,000 doing that, and I
could interact with them.
I knew what I wanted, and then they were
writing all the code and the PHP and
everything, and
So what got created over a couple of days I
think would have cost at least 10 or 15
grand.
Awesome.
And I asked Don, can you just repeat what
you created, Don?
Yeah.
I call it, I call it a pipeline management.
And so as a laser coming in and then they
get categorized and followed up on.
And, and so it just tracks the whole from
the beginning opportunity all the way to
the sale or, or, you know, discarding and,
and then keeping track of who are people
that are referring to us and, Those are all
Ascension opportunities.
So I've just really created a platform to
build on now because I couldn't control it
before we were locked into this stupid
FileMaker thing.
And now I can make it do whatever I want
from here just by asking Claude to do that
for me.
And it's amazing how fast it works.
So the latticework of what Don set up, it's a
super base.
It's basically he set up a database
architecture that he can put anything in,
right?
and then search for it and access it.
And so you could do a lot with that.
Like, so it sounds like you're doing mainly
CRM style functionality, but we were
talking on Wednesday in the office hours
about like, how do I dump my email or how
do I get, you know, Claude to get insights
around email?
You could dump all your email in there and
search it, right?
You can dump all your data in there and
search it.
So have you done any like vector mappings
yet done on that data?
No.
In fact, I actually made a note here to
investigate what a vector mapping is.
There you go.
Like, just go to that same cloud chat, but,
you know, you built this in and just ask,
hey, you know, can I add some vector
mapping to this, turn it into a RAG-like
database?
Yeah.
It'll explain it.
Uh-huh.
And I should mention that so far the Supra
is free.
It's really dirt cheap.
You're not paying for users or seats or
anything like that.
And so it created the whole login by users
with their passwords and password resets.
All of that stuff was done.
That took about 30 minutes.
So I think it's – so from here we can now –
deploy a lot of the ideas that come up out
of participating in this group rapidly and,
you know, demonstrating to, you know, to
equities owners in this what makes sense
and what's possible now that wasn't
possible last year.
Thanks, Don.
Jonas, did you have something you wanted
to say?
No, I was just encouraging FM to say
something.
Okay.
Because he was so polite.
Thank you, Jonas.
Very briefly, to answer the question that's
on the screen, we challenged the team to
just reinvent ourselves starting AI first.
And so we stood up a whole new
domain and process and team to compete
against the mothership, leveraging 20
years of experience and the people that we
have just to see if it'll stick.
And now we're working through the
motions, as you said, and I'm behind by
three sessions, so I haven't got as far as I
should be, but we're addressing some of
those things that we just saw on the slide,
which is also why I'm very engaged today
and vocal.
It's really hitting home immensely.
So thank you for that.
I can say
So, you know, I have an English school and
it's all in-person lessons in a small city.
So it's our students come.
I'm in Angola.
People like to learn in groups.
You know, we have 15 students in a group
and that's compared to like 50 or 60 in a
classroom.
And until earlier on, you said about that we
had to look for a competitor and
The last competitor we had in June, you
know, went out of business, but I just
looked and thinking, I think AI is going to
be our competitor.
It's a language school, you know, and, um,
and found one or two small ones that are
starting, but how I'm thinking is not to
substitute what we're doing, but to
enhance our, like to make a kind of
blended thing where we are helping our
existing students who want to come in
person.
It's very social, you know, they come in, it's
a place and there is like a very high positive
energy by coming and being with others.
but to speed up having them interact.
And I haven't, I'm just seeing what's all
these questions here of kind of ways to do
it, but we haven't moved yet, but that's
what this is provoking in me of how to
make little agents or tools that can be, you
know, homework assignments that you go
and practice speaking like this, and then
you come in class and do it in front of the
class with somebody else or something like
that.
Yeah, the environment, the environment in
my community,
especially in-person community is actually
something that that's probably the need
for that is going to grow.
But, and it's absolutely true that you will,
you know, you'll compete with more or less
free apps that have AI based English
language learning.
Right.
But there's always going to be a group of
people who are motivated by the
community side.
And, you know, if you think about like what
the job is that you're solving, it may not
just be teaching English, right?
It may be something a lot more like
emotional and connection based.
But if we can help our students actually
become fluent and talk, speak and
understand faster, they can even do that
more.
Yeah.
So a hundred percent implementing that as
homework is a, is a great idea.
Yeah.
Or designing a little app, like again, go to
cloud and design an app and put it on the
app store.
It takes no time now.
Yeah.
Okay.
So actually great segue, defensible
advantages using AI.
So brand is more important than ever,
right?
And having a human brand and thought
leadership becoming a trusted authority in
your space, just because there's gonna be,
everyone's gonna become overwhelmed
with options because the cost of content is
dropping so much.
So if you can, I would say you may have,
let's say six to 18 months, depending on
your industry, right?
You may have an opportunity to create a
bit of a brand moat and like invest heavily
in that space.
I would highly recommend you do that
because I think pretty much every industry
is going to see just a huge glut of content
coming out and everyone's going to end up
probably surfacing, even settling
even more on like real established,
established, um, brands.
Um, obviously this doesn't apply to
everyone.
Um, you know, proprietary data, um,
becomes data is more valuable today with
AI as for a lot of the reasons we went over
in some of the previous slides here.
Um, if there are network effects right in
your business, obviously that creates a
moat.
Um, actually a lot of, a lot of businesses
have network effects that they're not
aware of and they just don't know or
they're not optimizing for it, right?
So even Nancy, your business has network
effects, right?
The more students that come, the more
valuable it is for the group, right?
And so asking your LLM to help identify
some of these sort of defensible
advantages like network effects and how
to scale these, especially in like the next six
to 12 months
Um, it's probably a good practice.
Um, and then switching costs is an
interesting, it's an interesting thought
experiment.
Um, so what, what will the switching costs
be?
So if you actually take, if you take the path,
the AI path in your industry and chat with
AI a bit about it, actually try to understand
like, what will it cost my customers to
switch and who are they switching to in the
future?
Um, and then how can you almost develop
your product?
to make the integration deeper and the
switching costs higher, obviously without
making your product worse.
Again, exploring that path with AI, it will
help you learn important things about
where the future might be going in your
space.
Um, data can, again, depending on your
industry, uh, data has different types of
competitive advantages.
Um, at the very least, um, and we talked
about this in office hours, um, having more
data allows you to do more with that data
and feeding as long as you're able to feed
that data to AI.
And so we were talking even just about
like, I think, um, there are a couple of
people who have physical, you know,
in-person offices.
and their meetings aren't being recorded.
And so one of the first steps is like, how can
I just get that data and start making sure
all the meetings are recorded?
Because if all the meetings are recorded,
we have more data that we can act on.
We can set up agents that are
accountability buddies with each individual
person.
We can set up automated reporting so that
nobody is manually copying and pasting
numbers in.
And that's just one example, obviously,
Things like getting feedback from
customers, right?
So getting, that's useful data that you can
now mine and use a lot of the previous
things in this slide to explore how to create
better products, right?
And then there is a continuous
improvement loop that can be database
and agent-based.
That would be like the stage five-ish
businesses, right?
Or stage 4.5 businesses, right?
where if your data, if you get enough data
from customers that it informs your agents
well enough, your agents can continuously
improve.
Again, that's more, there are certain spaces
where that's a thing, but I think we're
gonna see more and more of that in the
coming years.
Again, here, ask your LLM, you know,
what's unique data we collect that
competitors don't have?
What, is unique data that we could collect,
right, that competitors wouldn't have, and
how can we use this to our advantage,
whether that's to build predictive models,
whether that's to create self-improving
agents, whether that's to improve more,
have better automation, have better
accountability, have better delegation, or
just have better productivity.
One other note here, and we'll get into this
in the next two sessions.
Your employees are a massive wealth of
data and knowledge, like a massive,
massive wealth.
So in the Teams program, our whole thing
is like a lot of tribal knowledge exists in
your employees' heads, but also a lot of
innovation exists in your employees' heads.
And we are starting to see like, for me at
least, for the first time, I'm starting to see a
lot of innovation in employees.
our companies and the companies we're
teaching that that's coming not from me.
And it's coming because it's people being
interviewed by AI with a certain lens on
that, that kind of creates all of these new
ideas and then the AI partnering with them
over time to develop the accountability
and kind of do what would have been a
top-down delegation approach.
So I would highly encourage to, Well, join
teams if you want.
But if not, talk to your setup prompts that
your employees can use that basically gets
data from your employees and then
creates really useful outputs with it.
And then feed that data into a database
that you can work with it.
Um, think ecosystem.
So with whatever you are, whatever your
company is, um, you may be providing a
service, right?
Um, instead of just providing a service,
think about, you know, building an
ecosystem.
Um, think about working with partners.
I think about referrals and network effects.
Think about marketplaces, right?
All of these things, uh, in my opinion,
ecosystems,
will be traded much more valuable than
services because ecosystems have an
innate network effect.
So one interesting prompt, again, more
exploratory, would be how could we
transform our service or our company into
an ecosystem that creates network effects
and partner value around a core business?
Don, I noticed your hand.
Can you hear me okay?
Yep.
Okay, great.
Just a really quick question.
The whole idea of mining, you know, the
capabilities of the employees, you said join
teams if you want.
And are you talking about using quad
teams or is there something else I'm
missing?
Oh, no.
We have a teams program, which we'll talk
about if people are interested.
But, you know, basically we do a custom
cohort for your teams.
Okay.
There's a small plug.
Joking.
Okay.
All right.
Great.
Um, so same idea if you were to, um, build
upon this concept, right.
Uh, ask what, uh, any, what an ecosystem
around your core business might look like,
right.
Uh, what partners, uh, what integrators,
um, what community elements would
create the most value?
I, again, this would be a nice little slide to
just kind of screenshot in, uh, and
understand.
I think just this process, whether or not
you do it, just this process, I think will give
you a lot of insight into potentially valuable
businesses in the future, whether that is
something you do or something somebody
else does.
I mentioned this before, but on the trend
side, I didn't put this in the prompt, but I
probably should have, and I'll edit it in the
homework.
So there's a framework to looking at a lot
of external changes called the PESTLE
framework, P-E-S-T-L-E.
So just ask it to do that.
It will likely see a lot of things you haven't
thought about in your industry, almost
certainly.
Okay.
Um, depending on your business stage, I,
this is actually more of a reminder to, to
just be aware and to right-size, uh, Claude
on, on some of the things that you, uh,
work on.
Right.
So if you're, if you're a startup, um, you
know, you probably should be focusing
more on single product market fit, um,
your timeline on, on sort of new product
cycles would be a lot shorter, right?
Maybe a month.
Um, and your feedback cycle from
customers needs to be a lot quicker.
Um, so just remember to keep this in mind,
um, and maybe remind Claude if it forgets,
um, again, just right-sizing, uh, right-sizing
for, let's say like a bit more of a growing
business, let's say one to $10 million in
revenue.
I, you, you likely have longer development
cycles, more budget, your feedback cycles
can be a little bit slower.
Um,
And this is typically, this is the business
that you're looking for, you know, that
expansion product or expansion products.
And then more established businesses,
again, this is revenue based, you know,
depending on your industry, this could be,
you know, 50 million or above, but you're
looking a little bit more about into like
portfolio optimization, right?
So what products, it's like more about like
revenue mix shift and you're looking at a
little bit more at defense, right?
And kind of building a moat.
And obviously you have the benefit of
having longer timelines with your strategic
planning.
So just right size this to your to your
business.
Silly question, but does the market
positioning activities equal R&D as well, or
is it a subsection or overarching on that?
You mean equal R&D and what?
Just in terms of the, as a percentage of
revenue, would you, is market positioning
activities equal R&D or is it a part of it?
Or I just want to make sure I understand
the context of what you're suggesting.
As like a budget item?
Yeah.
So I would say, yeah, new product service
development would be considered R and D
and would go into, if you're like budget
allocating would go into a R and D budget.
Testing new acquisition channels would be,
I would say a percentage of marketing
spend, which is slightly different.
And so I would, I would separate those.
Like I try to keep about 20 to 30%,
depending on the business of marketing
spends to test new things.
whether that's new things in the same
channel or new channels.
But yeah, on this side, again, it's not
expensive.
Like that, that's something that's really
important to know.
Like a lot of this stuff that we're going over
in these slides is something that you can
probably go from start to finish.
And by finish, I mean like, you know, you
have it on your website, you have
contracts, you're selling it and you have
process in place on how to fulfill it in like
under 30 days, so from a budget
perspective, I don't know how much you
need to allocate.
Probably more time than anything, but yes.
Yeah, it's really, it's more your own
attention, and in today's world, it's one of
five things that Claude is working on at a
time.
So yeah, I actually, so on the time and
money to invest.
So the time allocation is the biggest piece.
We're going to get into this in the next
session.
Like how should everybody be spending
their time going forward?
Yeah.
This is very ballpark.
And I don't think the numbers actually are
important.
I think it's more important that you
actually budget it.
And because the numbers can vary greatly
depending on your cash position,
depending on your business as a whole.
If you have no money in the bank, don't
budget any of this, go sell.
But the important item here is that you do
allocate allocate a piece and I would say
the biggest thing is allocating your time.
So either your time personally, or like your
AI operators time or whoever's AI enabled.
I look at the, I always played video games
growing up and I played like these RTS
games, which are like basically resource
management games.
And you could either build up your army or
you could build up your workers and your
economy and
Anyone who played these things, you have
to build up your economy first.
I look at this as your next step is to
AI-enable your team, and that is building
your economy.
Because the more people you arm with
this, the more time allocation you can put
into this.
Again, we'll go over that a little bit more in
the next session.
Yeah, how is everyone thinking right now
about your time allocation in relation to
AI?
Like in a given day, how?
Heavy.
For me, it's 50% of my day now.
Is that 50% of your day is used sort of
exploring and learning or 50% of your day
is just using AI?
All three.
So I try to spend time doodling.
I'm just experimenting another 25% with
the team, trying to part my knowledge and
get the head cheerleader for AI, although
I'm not doing as well a job as I should be.
And then the other one is
injecting process from what i've learned
doing AI, trying to do it and forcing our
engineering team to adopt it, even though
they're very stubborn.
That's awesome.
What's the size of your company in terms
of like number of employees or.
We have like 300 ish.
Okay.
Good size.
Anyone else want to share how they're
either currently allocating time or planning
on continuing to allocate time?
Yeah.
Since, um, being part of this cohort, I
increased allocation, but, uh, still too little,
um, uh, compared to what I wish.
I try to progress with the, yeah, with your
prompts.
and to get to the point, but in parallel, use
it also for decision making.
And yeah, this is new to me.
So it was like Googling with AI before.
Now it becomes more concepting, more
challenging.
For instance, customer quotes.
So are we targeting it correctly?
What do you think?
And then
Yeah, this is tremendous help, but still,
yeah, we are far away from using it as I
want to use it.
And that needs my time.
So it's really allocating the right resources.
And I think about new business models
using AI.
So just as a side note, also your service or
your awards brought me also to new
business model ideas I would like to follow.
I just need to first build the economy
before I can proceed because otherwise
otherwise you dig into new projects and
you, you will never finish it because you
are dispersed.
Yeah.
That's the new challenge is that there's so
many things going on, keeping track of it
all and closing loops on things is very
difficult.
One thing i would say is that, you know,
you mentioned doodling FM, like that's,
absolutely right.
Um, and there was a period in time where I
sort of just, I was kind of doing a lot of
things since I probably, I stopped doodling
for like, I don't know, maybe two or three
weeks.
And I remember I went to the gym with
Tiago and I kind of complained about it and
he encouraged me to like, you know,
actually I didn't complain about it.
I said, I was working on this other thing.
And then he said, you know, you're gonna
lose your edge because you're no longer
learning.
And so, I went home and that was the day,
um, that I learned cloud code and I, that,
you know, that piece of learning for me
was worth, I don't, I don't know.
I can't, I couldn't put a number on it.
Right.
But, um, so I think allocating a certain
amount of your time to, to trying
something new, um, is really important
and thinking about like, what is your
trigger for yourself to try something new?
Right.
So for example, do you like, you know,
watching YouTube videos and like tutorials
and just playing along?
That's a great way, right?
That's something new and you'll learn
something about it and you'll figure out
how to apply it to what you're doing.
Or sometimes it's just like, take a function
in your business and just ask how AI can do
it, right?
So the Elon Musk sort of like, go find the
constraint and like work with the
developer who is like directly dealing with
that constraint and help, help them do
that.
That same kind of approach is like, go, go
find the constraint from like a process
perspective and then work with something
like cloud code to figure out, can you do
something with this?
Right.
And just go systematically, right.
Put it on your calendar to go systematically
process through process or, you know,
starting with your, your constraints from
the, um,
you know, highest constraint down or
bottleneck.
I found those two to be like, those are the
two things that usually keep me or
prioritize my doodling.
Another general comment to make, and it's
like a couple of people in this cohort, right,
who are also were in the first cohort.
And I mean, I very consciously when you
made the offer that there would be like
four more of them knew I wanted to go in
the last one, because I wanted to see what
we could do before that.
And then my experience this, it's like, when
moved over to Claude teams, and I haven't
wanted to move over all my stuff, and I've
been quite careful, but now in the last one
about the organizational and leadership
I'm going into that and, you know, it's
really taking me deep in remembering how
I did I start this and, you know, all the, like
writing all of this stuff about the past to
the present and this experiment of getting
my team.
We did it today.
We didn't work everybody on the phone,
but had like six people answering a bunch
of these questions.
And now you keep giving this other idea,
like just ask Claude, what are we going to,
what, you know, what things could I do?
And I did it right as you were starting.
And it just gave me a whole process of,
what I could do and make a map of who's
doing the same things and what, what,
what the clarity boards could be.
And so they like, I'm in this, I don't know,
the first cohort felt like holding onto the
back of Superman's cape, you know, and
now I just feel in the midst of the whole
world falling apart.
It's so interesting.
And these, I'm still in the iterative process,
right?
I don't know if we can afford teams, but
this being able to come back and in a way
go back and then you're,
off doing what you can, but you get back by
being in the cohort and going through this.
It's kind of thrilling.
I'm very glad to have had that opportunity
and will look for more to help to structure
that.
I guess that's what it feels like with all this
AI.
Here is a roadmap that we're following to
whatever extent it's possible to follow,
which some of it I'm just not, but pieces of
it, it just seems that we're on I feel like I'm
on a road and it's a good road and I'm
getting good advice and off we go.
And that's my comment.
Yeah.
It's, it's over.
The pace of change is overwhelming.
It's and, and it's, it's exponential, right?
Like the time between models is dropping
exponentially.
Model updates is dropping exponentially,
but in the quality of the update is getting
larger.
So, and it's because all of, all of the AI firms
have,
increasingly become AI first and are using
their own, you know, everything's coded in
cloud code and codex and nobody is writing
code anymore.
So yeah, it's a big challenge to determine
like what is signal versus noise in the
space.
And I think having a group like
participating in circle and, you know, we
should probably coordinate more office
hours going forward and stuff, just having
a group to see what people have learned
and played with.
Uh, one thing I, I, a lot of this is designed
for is like, this is very much.
There is a, there are like fundamentals of,
I'd say like AI adoption and enablement for
an individual.
And, and I think that this cohort is very
much designed to get you past sort of into
that ready to enter sort of that cloud code
zone.
Right.
Um, so I would say most people, the next
step should be go install cloud code or
codex.
Both are good.
If you're not a developer, you don't have to
actually install it through the command
line interface or terminal.
You can literally just download the Cloud
app and run it from there, and it's a lot less
intimidating.
But if I could give you some advice if you
haven't used it, that's the next step.
If you can, spend a few hours, and that's
also very thrilling.
You'll feel very powerful.
Sorry, Hayden, I interrupted you.
I've never felt more powerful from just the
incredible ability of output.
Once you're able to do that, you just feel all
powerful.
I can't explain it.
I don't mean that in a bad way.
You just feel incredibly competent until
Cloud Code goes down.
And speaking of Cloud Sorry, Christina.
Yeah.
So you said that's the next step.
I haven't tried it yet.
For me, it was really if I want to build
something new.
Could you give us just maybe some use
cases and easy ones to start off with?
So I...
You know what I'll do?
The last session is going to be like almost
half office hours.
And so I think I'll do it then just because we
only have eight minutes right now.
I would say if you want to go out and get
started, one really quick, interesting, fast
hack.
Does anyone here use Obsidian?
Yeah.
Okay.
Uh, so obsidian is like, uh, kind of like a
note taker, like Evernote or one note, but it
uses Markdown files.
Um, and, and it's just hosted, um, in a, in a
subdirectory.
It's a cloud code.
Um, it gets hosted in a subdirectory of your
computer and then cloud can control any
files within that subdirectory.
Um, so one little thing to start out with is
use cloud code or codex install obsidian.
put your vault in the codex subdirectory
and start playing with Cloud Code
controlling Obsidian.
Even if all you're doing is like using Cloud
Code as literally just prompting, now you
can take everything that you do and feed it
into Obsidian, which is kind of similar to
what Don's doing with his database.
And from there, so even like a very simple
example, so my to-do, right, and all of my
projects are all in Obsidian.
But I just write, I don't even really use
Obsidian much.
I usually just tell Cloud Code what to do.
And it goes and it organizes all my notes,
right, and it tags everything.
And I can ask it.
So, for example, working on the right next
thing, you know, it will tell me what's on
my to-do for today.
And then I can tell it, what can you do for
my to-do?
And then it'll get started and we'll work
back and forth on it.
But this wouldn't work with OneNote, for
instance, because I also work with
OneNote.
So I moved from OneNote to Obsidian.
And I would really recommend you do so as
well.
OneNote is very outdated.
I've used it for 20 years.
But it's my second brain.
And Notion versus Obsidian?
So Notion is more of like a cloud-based
tool.
and it's kind of got its own ecosystem that
it tries to bring you into.
I'm just naturally averse to that.
I'm more of an open source guy, like to be
able to control things.
Usually it's like Notion versus ClickUp is
kind of the question.
And maybe the obsidian thing isn't right.
I mean, that's something to look into,
especially for any other OneNote users.
The other thing with Cloud Code, that
would be like a really simple thing.
So what I do in Cloud Code is I basically
take the same fundamentals that we
taught here and I set up my directory
structure to have my companies.
And then within each company, there's a
subdirectory for resources, processes,
priorities.
And within processes, I have all my
processes.
And so when you do that, so Cloud Code
can use, can navigate and search around all
of your folders to find whatever files it
needs.
And so one of the first things you can do is
put some processes in there and then just
tell Cloud Code, go follow my processes,
right?
Do this thing, follow my processes.
And so just having all of that context in one
place is like a massive level up, even over
what we have right now as a master
prompt, because it has now this flexible
context to follow everything in your
business.
Right?
Because everything will fall into either a
resource, a process, or a priority.
Okay.
Can you just do, give me a link, because i
haven't looked at it yet, but i had signed up
for tiago's notion template thinking of of
also implementing that, and that's how i
got to notion how does is is that only like
kind of on a personal basis, or how do you
bring these worlds together?
You just
talked about the register with the different
companies and like, how did you do your
ecosystem?
You mean like, how do I merge the
personal and the.
Yeah.
Or like, would I be setting up, could I also
be setting up Tiago's template in obsidian?
Would you recommend that for what we're
doing here?
And so, yeah, that brings us to the world's
merging kind of.
I, yeah.
So I would say.
So all I can explain is how I do it.
Um, so Claude, I typically work locally, um,
you know, either cloud code or codex in the
same directories and the equivalent of my
master prompts or across my subject,
those directories, including personal, um,
and obsidian is my vault that holds
everything.
It's my, my one note now.
Right.
But the difference is, whereas in one note, I
had the habit of, okay, I'm having a
meeting.
I'll go right.
And I'll take notes here.
Now I just do it in cloud code, but I have a
skill to write
to obsidian.
Right.
And I'll just say, put this in obsidian.
And then every once in a while I'll say,
organize everything in obsidian.
And every once in a while I say like,
imagine you could talk to one note and you
could say, you know, what items on my
to-do can you get started on right now?
And it would just go and do stuff.
Right.
Or ask you a couple of questions and then
go and do stuff like that.
That's what you can do if you put the
certain, right.
And it costs nothing.
Yeah.
If you do it in notion, you're, you're, The
only issue is that you then fall into notions
ecosystem to do it, which means you need
to use notions AI.
You need to use notion, like you don't have
the same flexibility.
So I don't like that personally, but some
people like that.
Otherwise Apple wouldn't exist.
Really interesting.
Thank you.
I'll just mention that I had dumped all of
my stuff into Markdown files.
And I dropped all of those into Notebook
LM and hit the button that said make a
mind map.
And that was useful.
Probably 10 or 15 years of notes, you know,
and it's just like, what am I really doing
here?
And I kind of broke it off in the mind map
and then try to create structure and, you
know, try and understand what I really had
to be doing today.
Right.
That's one of, that's another, yeah, it's the
same idea.
I'd say that's like one of, there are three
kind of approaches to the same concept.
And one of them is using notebook LM and
using the notebook LM skill within cloud
code or, or building one.
So if you look at your YouTube videos,
there's lots of YouTube videos.
around this, around people who basically
use Cloud Code with Notebook LM and
have them speak to each other.
The main reason you want to do this would
be to save tokens, because Notebook LM
can do a lot of processing on its own for
free.
And to share the notebooks, that's useful.
And then to use the functionality that
Notebook LM innately does, like building
presentations and building podcasts and
videos and mind maps.
So that's one, so Notebook LM is one, so
Cloud Code to Notebook LM is one, Cloud
Code to Obsidian is another, and then
Cloud Code to like Supabase and like your
own custom database would be another,
but that's a lot more complex.
That's nothing these days.
I'm an expert now.
I started three days ago.
When you tell Cloud Code to put it in
Obsidian, what is it doing?
Just dumping a bunch of stuff into a note?
Yeah, so Obsidian is just a vault.
So it's a folder.
It's called your vault.
And then everything are just .md files.
And when you create a new node, it's just a
.md file.
Everything's in Markdown.
You don't need to do anything.
You can just tell Cloud Code to go install
stuff.
Yeah, it's worth checking out for people
who've been meaning to bring their, say,
second brain note-taking system to the
next level.
I can't answer on the Notion side because I
don't use it, but I can definitely answer
here and help out.
I mentioned that, you know, grabbing the
notes, I mastered that.
Organizing them, not so much.
And so in honor of Tiago, I also installed the
Notion template and started using that,
and my productivity surged right away.
I started getting really important stuff
done, you know, and setting aside the
others.
So it would be nice to get everything
integrated.
My next question I'm going to investigate is
what can I export out of motion that will
make sense?
So our next session is on Monday.
So we have one on Monday and one on
Friday.
And then I think no office hours next week.
But a lot of Friday will be open.
The homework for this session, there's
really only like the kind of the process
development side.
There's no assessment for product service
development because most people don't
have a process for it.
Um, and then there's a lot of optional
homework, um, for those that want to do
it.
Um, and I would also say every single
prompt on pretty much every single slide
of this deck is optional homework.
Um, again, I think just putting it in, if
something's seems relevant to you, just
like screenshotting it, putting it in and like
spending five minutes talking with AI can
be quite enlightening, um, and can teach
you something maybe about what I, what
AI can do that you weren't aware of.
Um, so.
If you can, get to the optional stuff.
If not, that's fine.
Awesome.
Thank you everyone.
Have a great weekend.
Thank you.
You too.
Happy Friday.
Take care.
Bye-bye.